Peter Andreou-Rodriguez, MBA

Summary

LinkedIn • Towaco, NJ 07082

Analytical and trilingual professional with diverse experience in formulating construction/design documents. Hardworking, collaborative and dedicated individual with proficient organizational skills to efficiently oversee projects from planning to completion. Adept at understanding project contracts to establish project objectives, coordinating all assigned activities for ontime project delivery and identifying clients' expectations to attain budgetary constraints through meetings with clients. Articulate communicator with strong diligence skills. Recently completed Masters of Business Administration with classes in Engineering Project Management from University of Southern Indiana and currently pursuing Architect's Registration Exams (ARE's) to gain status of registered architect with clearance of three of the exams.

Technical Proficiencies

Key Skills

Architectural Design | Quality Assurance | Contracts Administration | Consultant & Client Communication Construction Evaluation & Management | Relationship Building | Report Generation

Software

Autodesk AutoCAD | Autodesk Revit/BIM Modeling | BIM 360 | Rhino 3D Modeler | MS Office Suite ProjectLibre | Adobe Illustrator | Adobe In-Design | Adobe Photoshop | Adobe PDF editor

Experience Highlights

Netta Architects, Mountainside, NJ Project Architect

2018 - 2021

Completed variety of project's architectural design/construction drawings within defined timelines. Mapped out construction contract drawings and specification documents for projects. Collaborated with clients, consulting engineers, construction & general contractors, as well as other specialized design consultants throughout the design and construction processes. Analyzed code requirements for building and site designs. Delivered construction administration services and construction progress meeting attendance resulting in achievement of desired project outcomes. Building design experience in a variety of building typologies including Municipal, Educational, Corporate/Office, Industrial and several housing projects.

- Utilized Revit 3D/BIM modeling and AutoCAD drafting for all contract and design documents.
- Created building use diagrams and schematic drawings / diagrams for presentation.
- Developed reports & drawings following survey of project sites for ongoing construction progress and new projects.
- Reviewed construction submittals / shop drawings for design intent and construction use.

Architectural Designer – Internship

2016 - 2017

Facilitated project architects in creation of architectural and construction drawings. Participated in construction meetings and collaborated on projects with project architects and project managers. Instrumental in ensuring compliance with construction/design documentation's quality control and best practices.

- Conducted project surveys to evaluate new jobs and existing construction progress.
- Interacted with clients to approve project requirements, budget, and schedule.

New Jersey Transit (Capital Planning and Programming Department), Newark, NJ Construction Management Department – Internship

2014 - 2015

Assisted in construction document control and progress under defined capital. Involved with department strategy meetings for NJ Transit rail and bus improvement projects. Aided in archival of construction drawing and review.

- Engaged in construction meetings to prepare reports on important key points for future discussion regarding project execution.
- Conducted project site visits to evaluate construction progress and planning

Education

Masters of Business Administration, 2022 | University of Southern Indiana, IN

Bachelor of Architecture with Minor in Environmental Studies and Sustainability, 2018 | New Jersey Institute of Technology – College of Architecture, Newark, NJ

Montville Township High School, Montville, NJ, 2013

Skills: Architectural & Technical Drafting, Digital Design/Website Design and I.T. Classes

Languages | English, Spanish and Greek - Fluent

Volunteer Experience | American Institute of Architecture Students & Sustainability and Energy Club NJIT